Alex Manning

Allandale, Abbey Foregate, Shrewsbury, SY2 6BL **M** 07816970597

E <u>alexiwmanning@gmail.com</u>

An accomplished brand and creative strategist with over six years' experience in dynamic creative environments.

I have a passion for helping brands to solve their thorniest marketing and business challenges in exciting and effective ways, built upon a lucid understanding of human psychology and behaviour.

Employment and Experience

Cult LDN

January 2021 - present: Associate Strategy Director

October 2018 - December 2020: Senior New Business Strategist January 2017 - September 2018: Insights & Research Manager

- Lead strategist on Cult's new business drive; responsible for all strategic elements of the pitch process, from reception of the brief to presentation of our strategic and creative solutions.
- Lead strategist for DIESEL and Rodan + Fields, while working across various other Cult clients in the beauty, fashion, luxury and wellness sectors.
- I have also authored a series of thought leadership reports, building the agency's reputation and generating leads through targeted outreach.
- During my tenure, the agency has celebrated its most profitable year, opened a new office in New York and been shortlisted for Independent Agency of the Year in Campaign's Agency of the Year awards.
- Clients we have won with my participation include Netflix, Burberry, Nike, Rodan + Fields, Umbro, NBC Universal, American Eagle Outfitters, Farfetch, Tod's, DIESEL, Kopari, Amazon Fashion, Royal Salute, ELEMIS, Defra, Dunhill, MAC Cosmetics, TOPSHOP Beauty, Carolina Herrera, and Pepsi Lipton.

Naked Communications

July 2016 - December 2016: Senior New Business Executive

July 2015 - June 2016: New Business Executive

January 2015 - June 2015: Account Executive Intern

- Made a permanent employee after six months and subsequently promoted to Senior New Business Executive after a further year.
- I expanded my role beyond supporting pitches and outreach to helping to define the growth strategy of the agency, writing thought leadership pieces and owning tone of voice on case studies and documents for prospective clients.
- I played a key role in generating new business opportunities across various industries and sectors, as well as running thought leadership events with attendees from brands, intermediaries and industry bodies.

Education

2010-2014: University of Oxford

MA (Hons) Literae Humaniores; Grade 2:1

2005-2010: King's College School, Wimbledon

42 (out of 45) in IB; at Higher Level: Spanish 7, Latin 7, English 7; at Standard Level: Biology 7,

Maths Studies 7, History 6; 1 bonus point

10 GCSEs: 6 A*, 4 A A in AS Level Latin

Interests and Skills

Outside of work, I enjoy spending time with my two young children and practicing a variety of sports, including football, golf, tennis and cross-country running. I'm an ardent supporter of Fulham Football Club. I also enjoy overseas travel, having travelled extensively throughout Europe, and I'm a keen linguist, capable of conversational Spanish, moderately proficient in French and currently learning Italian. I regard myself as capable, diligent and friendly.

References

Available upon request.